Preliminary Inventory to the Harvard University Russian Research Center Interview Transcripts, 1950-1951
Hoover Institution Archives
Harvard University Russian Research Center Interview Transcripts,
1950-1951
XX727
Harvard University. Russian Research Center.
26 manuscript boxes (10.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Mimeographed transcripts of interviews of refugees from the Soviet Union, conducted in West Germany and the United States by the Harvard University Russian Research Center, relating to social conditions in the Soviet Union.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Social conditions.
Container List
- Announcements in Russian and Ukrainian for the interviews (Box 1)
- Questionnaire
- Condensed interviews
- Unknown versions of interviews
- A Schedule interviews (Box 2)
  - General
  - Experimental
  - Munich experimental
  - Version 2. #16, 23, 25, 28, 34, 48, 53, 57, 58, 60, 62, 73, 88
  - Version 3
    - #1-5
    - #6-14, 17-20, 24, 26, 29-32 (Box 3)
    - #40, 45-47, 49, 51, 54, 59, 61, 64, 66, 74, 85, 86, 90 (Box 4)
  - Version 4 - Final Questionnaire
    - #25, 33, 41, 64, 67
    - #91-97, 100-105, 107-115 (Box 5)
    - #116, 118, 119, 121, 124, 125-134, 136, 138, 139, 142, 143, 144 (Box 6)
    - #145, 148, 149, 153, 156, 159, 167, 175, 176, 179, 188, 189, 190, 191 (Box 7)
    - #240, 258, 260, 266, 273, 275, 284-287, 300-309, 314, 318, 319, 323 (Box 8)
    - #324, 325, 330-342, 344, 345, 349, 351 (Box 9)
    - #355, 357-360, 373, 378, 380, 381, 385-387, 393-395, 398, 399, 407, 415 (Box 10)
    - #416, 417, 419-421, 423, 425, 431-434, 438, 445-447, 449, 451, 452, 454 (Box 11)
    - #455, 456, 468, 470-479, 481, 483, 487, 490, 491 (Box 12)
    - #492, 493, 494, 501, 507, 511, 513, 514, 516-526 (Box 13)
    - #527-532, 534-537, 539-541, 601, 611, 622, 623, 628-633 (Box 14)
    - #634, 638-644, 646, 1007, 1011, 1035, 1053, 1069, 1091, 1106, 1109, 1123, 1124, 1173 (Box 15)
    - #1204, 1215, 1240, 1241, 1281, 1296, 1313, 1350, 1354, 1368, 1390, 1398, 1434, 1441, 1451, 1460, 1462, 1467 (Box 16)
    - #1486, 1492, 1493, 1495, 1497, 1498, 1507, 1517, 1528, 1578, 1582, 1654, 1664, 1684, 1693, 1705, 1706 (Box 17)
    - #1719, 1720, 1728, 1738, 1745 (Box 18)
  - Special interviews. #39, 105, 121, 374, 381, 391, 470 (Box 19)
  - Continuing interviews. #144
  - Fragments. #156, 166
  - Index of materials compiled in oral interviews
- B Schedule interviews
  - General
    - #22, 23, 25, 30, 40, 41, 45, 48, 56, 64, 67, 77, 99, 101, 105, 122, 126, 131
    - #133, 136, 140, 143, 144, 147, 182, 188, 193, 206, 220, 240, 258, 260, 270, 300, 301, 307, 344, 347, 355, 356, 359, 371, 372, 379, 382, 391, 400, 401, 426, 428, 441, 470, 488, 489, 490, 606, 607, 609, 635, 1379, 1533, 1700, 1725, 1757, 1758, 1800 (Box 20)
  - Version 2 - Economics. #16, 25, 26, 30, 31, 36, 37, 45, 49, 64, 65, 70, 90, 105, 114, 149, 164, 185, 190, 202, 220, 251, 304, 311, 316, 320, 384, 388, 396, 403, 405, 427, 430, 450, 470, 480, 481, 485, 516, 517, 524, 532, 609, 610, 611, 615, 637 (Box 21)
  - Version 5 - Nationalities. #15, 21, 23, 24, 45, 52, 62, 68, 71, 81, 89, 106, 121, 122, 135, 160, 163, 165, 182, 221, 224, 228, 252, 346, 352, 354, 356, 375, 383, 427, 431, 434, 448, 482, 495, 497, 502-506, 508, 641, 642, 1805 (Box 22)
  - Version 6
    - #7, 15, 22, 23, 27, 30, 32, 33, 46, 55, 59, 64, 67, 76, 78, 81, 89, 96
    - #101, 102, 105, 106, 121, 122, 135, 138, 141, 143, 144, 147, 160, 175, 182, 219, 314, 321, 317, 322, 354, 356, 358, 359, 373, 382, 384, 391, 429, 433, 439, 440, 441, 485, 488, 500, 510, 533, 542, 543, 545, 546, 548, 650, 651 (Box 23)
  - Version 8. #98, 360, 441, 446, 645
  - Version 9 - Clinical.
    - #2, 25, 41, 56, 64, 66, 93, 102, 105, 108, 121
    - #126, 133, 136, 144, 145, 147, 213, 258, 272, 277, 313, 349, 355, 358, 360, 381, 386, 431, 446, 447, 470, 472, 484, 641 (Box 24)
  - Version 10. #25, 27, 67, 121, 124, 147, 159, 175, 176, 285, 301, 372, 381, 385, 388, 391, 402, 403, 408, 409, 440, 441, 470, 491, 492, 494 (Box 25)
  - Version 11. #105, 139, 353, 376, 424, 449, 453, 486, 608, 1158, 1759, 1790
  - Communication. #67 (Box 26)
  - Family. #49, 64, 66, 67, 72, 113, 139, 213, 275, 279, 288, 296